Sariha McIntyre

Cell phone: (425) 412-0620 sariha.mcintyre@gmail.com

Sales Manager who is a university graduate with leadership experience ranging from teaching to supervisory positions. Previous work experience has provided a varied skill set including: property & casualty insurance and telecommunication sales experience, managerial leadership; program planning, conflict resolution, training, security and administrative duties. Well versed in oral/written communication and implementation of policies and procedures.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Zoology, biochemistry emphasis in marine animal systems July 2014; University of Hawai`i at Manoa

- Graduated summa cum laude; Dean's List student for all semesters
- o 3.97 cumulative GPA
- o Second Language: Latin

Associate of Art and Science Degree June 2011; Everett Community College

Running Start Program: Ocean Research College Academy (ORCA)

- Graduated with High Honors and Dean's List student
- o 3.93 cumulative GPA

EMPLOYMENT

Red Ventures—Fort Mill, South Carolina

Performance Coach

March 2015-Current

Title change from Performance Manager to Performance Coach in May 2017. Transferred to Verizon FiOS during this time, leading a team of 11+ agents and fulling leadership duties

From March 2015-May 2017 led a team of 5-11 insurance agents; trained new agents on how to write and sell insurance policies, as well as provided continuing education for veteran agents. Trained Floor Leads and Performance Managers in Training; drove profit by applying product, software and salesmanship knowledge while working to cultivate high team moral and positivity within the business.

Insurance Agent September 2014-March 2015

Sold home and auto insurance for multiple companies servicing numerous states, maintaining high professional and quality assurance standards. Consistently demonstrates effective communication skills to build rapport with myriad personality types in order to provide excellent customer experience.

Charlotte Christian School— Charlotte, North Carolina

August 2014-September 201 (part-time)

Extended Day Teacher

Supervised and coordinated children after-school activities in accordance with school procedures. Respond to emergency situations, mediate conflicts and communicate positively and effectively with children (K-6th grade) and parents.

University of Hawai'i at Manoa— Honolulu, Hawai'i

Laboratory Assistant

May-July 2014 (seasonal employment)

Assisted in teaching Cellular and Molecular Biology Laboratory for Summer Session I 2014. Helped students conduct experiments including gel electrophoresis, SDS-PAGE, and various DNA analytical methods such as Polymerase Chain Reaction. Along with teaching, duties also included preparing the laboratories for four different laboratory classes.

Teaching Intern (TI)

January 2014-May 2014 (seasonal employment)

Lectured and led directed discussion groups for two different recitation sections with 20-35 students for Cellular and Molecular Biology. Actively engaged students using humor, visual aids, relevant metaphors, and lively language to teach a supplemental lecture covering relevant topics in cellular and molecular biology. Administered and graded quizzes, main lecture class exams, and homework.

Resident Advisor/Resident Assistant (RA)

summers)

January 2012-May 2014 (excluding

Managed multiple residence hall floors composed of approximately thirty ethnically diverse undergraduates while working with a staff of twenty Resident Assistants. Assisted residents with security, technology-related issues, personal development and academic growth. Enforced housing policy both on duty during on-call hours and off duty by responding to inappropriate behavior, writing incident reports, and maintained confidentiality following FERPA regulations. Experience also includes event programming, administrative and student development responsibilities.

Georgia Institute of Technology, School of Biology, Aquatic Chemical Ecology Research Experience for Undergraduates Program— Atlanta, Georgia

May-July 2013 (10 week internship)

Research Intern

Worked in an oceanographic research lab and participated in a two week research cruise on the R/V *Endeavor* in the Gulf of Mexico, assisting to operate a Conductivity-Temperature-Depth (CTD) Rosette and Multiple Opening and Closing Net Environmental Sampling System (MOCNESS). Sampled surface seawater and conducted a personal triplicate experiment on the response of *Trichodesmium* spp., dinoflagellates and diatoms to Nitrate, Phosphate and Silicate nutrient amendments over a forty-eight hour incubation period.

National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration; Northwest Fisheries Science Center—Seattle, Washington

May-July 2012 (10 week internship)

Research Intern

Conducted field work (townetting, fiking, jelly fishing) related to monitoring and restoring Puget Sound wetland habitats and local specie population. Worked in a lab performing duties such as: utilizing microscopy to quantify and identify larval fish from plankton samples, as well as perform fish dissections and preserved tissue samples for isotopic research. Synthesized and analyzed previously collected data, interpreted results and present to NOAA scientist at NOAA headquarters in Washington D.C.

Shoreline Pool—Shoreline, Washington

March 2011-August 2011, June-July 2012 (left for college)

Lifeguard, Swim Lesson Instructor and Cashier

Yost Pool—Edmonds, Washington

June-September 2009, 2010, and 2011 (seasonal employment)

Lifeguard, Swim Lesson Instructor, Dive Coach and Water Aerobics Instructor

HONORS

Phi Beta Kappa member as of 2014

National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration Hollings Scholar 2011-2013

All-Washington 2011 Academic Team Scholar representative for Everett Community College

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

Ultimate Frisbee

Charlotte Ultimate Frisbee Manoa Ultimate Disk Club

January 2015-Present August 2011-May 2014

Weddington United Methodist Church

Leader of High School Sunday school, teaches bible study and organizes monthly social events.

December 2015- Present

Computer Systems

Microsoft operating systems, including Word, Excel, PowerPoint Online security systems, including Onity and Lenel

Google documents

SPSS and other statistical analysis systems